Greetings!
I'm Lastismoon and I currently handle
diplomatic relations here at the village.
The Crazy Dragon
Lastismoon
Please call me Lasty!
And I am Flowrem.
Daughter of the Count
Flowrem Chrome
Let us show you around the village.
The fields run from here to
the far end you can see!
Much too expansive to show you around it all.
Oh! Tomatoes here!
Beastwoman
Sena
I mean, I'm Sena, and these are tomatoes!
I'm Donovan, the Elder Dwarf.
Cross
Elder Dwarf
Donovan
Wilcox
We produce the alcohol.
I'm Ya, the Mountain Elf.
Mountain Elf Leader
Ya
We're great at crafting things!
Ready?
Yeah!
The Ancient Dragon
Hakuren
You've done well to reach us.
Rest now at ease.
Vampire Princess
Lu Lulucy
That seems a bit overboard.
But first impressions are key.
Maybe for visitors from afar.
Angel of Annihilation
Tia
But this is for new residents.
High Elf
Lea
No need to be so stiff day after day.
I suppose not.
Nice and friendly should do it, I think.
Now, how about some closing words?
Lu's Cousin
Flora
Flora's Familiar
Kamera
Oh, from me?
Who else?
Once again, then...
I'm Mayor Hiraku.
Welcome to The Great Tree Village!
The Story So Far
So far
I wanted to live
a peaceful farming life.
With some divine intervention,
I got the farm life I wanted
in an alternate world.
I've made so many new friends.
And now I'm the mayor of
The Great Tree Village,
a place we all built together.
Here you go.
Now, the reason our little village...
Umm...
is a bit more active today...
Over there!
Let's do this.
All done.
We need to find places for them to live.
So many people.
Plus the refugees.
Over 100 New Residents
...is because we were expecting
a great number of new residents.
With that many, we might need
a whole other village.
Why not make one, then?
A new village for all the new residents.
I'll scout out a new location!
I wonder where's best.
And just like that...
Time to chop down some trees!
...the whole village set to work.
We need lots of preserved food.
The hunt begins then.
Welcome to
The Great Tree Village
We got so excited we even began practicing.
Welcome to
The Great Tree Village
I need more smiles!
Maybe we should relax things a bit?
These are grapes!
Oh! This is new.
Made with ingredients which spoil quickly
Ogre Head Maid
Anne
so that we might focus our efforts on
increasing our supply of preserves.
That explains all the vegetables.
Let's treat the girls to the same.
Good thinking.
This is perfect for eating on the job.
I'll bring it to them myself.
Thank you.
Flow did mention being extra busy.
Village Hall
Village Clerk
Klakkase
This is impossible...
There's no way.
Village Clerk
Roaju
My ghost will haunt this place.
Village Clerk
Rosalind
I brought you all some lunch.
We're a little busy!
A "little?"
It's nearly impossible to keep track
of food and material stores.
Helping Out
Having a lot is good though, right?
A lot plus more equals a whole bunch...
That takes care of that!
What have you done?!
Don't worry, Flow is bringing help, right?
Sorry for the wait!
Help from the Demonic Kingdom has arrived.
We were told we'd be aiding Lady Flowrem...
That it would advance our social standing...
That the work was simple enough
for anyone to do...
Let's get right to it, then!
We'll start by organizing
our records into categories.
New Recruits
What about the all-you-can-eat apples?
And the limitless pet-pets?
Aren't you the daughter of House Puugal?
I'd heard you were missing
after being attacked by lamia.
What?!
I'm surprised to see you alive.
We should be able to handle
all our paperwork now.
Share this with everyone
once things settle down.
Thank you!
Clerks
Clerical Team
Limitless Pet-pets
Sir!
I’ve surveyed the area.
I found no signs of danger.
Angel of Annihilation
Granmaria
I sent her out.
We should go see the potential spot
for the new village.
Oh, great idea.
Should we make preparations?
Meals for the road?
It's not that far off.
Great Tree Village
The location we're considering
River
will be downstream so that
we might retain the upper hand.
Downstream
The upper hand in what?
To ensure our safety
in the worst circumstances,
it will be on the
far side of the river.
It will also stand some distance
from the river itself
to ensure the village
does not seize control of it.
Distance
What worst circumstances?
Rebellion.
Rebellion
You're assuming
that will happen?
We must at least be
prepared for as much.
It will be too late once it does.
Fair point.
It's not quite as great as our own,
but the area has its own standout tree.
Easy enough to spot.
Possible Location
Once we had the location,
Great Tree Village
Possible Location
we set about clearing the forest
to make a road.
Let's begin.
Here goes!
Hup! Hah!
Take this!
Progress
This won't do.
We lack the power.
It's tougher than steel.
Could you do your usual?
Sure.
Axe!
Wonton noodles!
Success!
Dandan noodles!
Champon noodles!
It was easy work with
my almighty farming tool.
Noodles! Noodles! Noodles!
We set up a wooden bridge across the river.
Shouldn't we build something sturdier?
If we make it too big...
Hup! Hah!
...large monsters might make use of it.
Hadn't thought of that.
After that...
Noodles! Noodles! Noodles!
We cleared out the area for the new village.
And uhh... mapo noodles!
Then built irrigation ducts.
Reservoir
Workshop
Impressive progress in such a short time.
Wouldn't be able to get much done
without enough lumber.
Please get some rest.
We'll handle the construction.
Sure.
There!
A monument to Zabuton.
Maybe I should have made it bigger.
You know...
I was told you were resting.
I am, sort of.
Papa sure loves work.
Oh yes, he does.
Okay okay, I'll take a break.
Break Time
Looks okay.
Things are moving right along.
I'd wondered why you were
preparing so much lumber.
We have plenty of houses to build, after all.
Foundation
Long Ones
Short Ones
I got all the lumber our plans called for prepped.
And had everyone else
break into teams to get them put up.
It was hard work building things
for myself back in the day.
Didn't even have nails back then.
Remember that little shack? Good times.
I remember how hard it was
lifting all that wood.
Wait...
This isn't the right length.
That goes here.
Oh, right.
Are you all right?
Surprisingly, yes...
Magic sure is something.
Next.
Here you are.
We need more boards, hm?
We do.
Hey!
Coming!
Oh! Are you all right?
Surprisingly, yes...
Lumber Tossing Forbidden
Safety first.
With everyone's help,
things are really coming together.
How many residents are we expecting?
We still don't really have concrete numbers.
Sir!
Forgive the intrusion.
I have a message from Lord Dryme.
He says he is bringing new residents now.
Seriously?
Do excuse the haste.
The situation was more pressing
than anticipated.
Gatekeeper Dragon
Dryme
You could have sent word.
Hm? I did just that.
I sent a messenger wyvern.
Ah, but I may have outpaced it.
I was in just that much a hurry.
These are the minotaurs
who wish to move here.
These are minotaurs?
Expectations
I expected
cow-headed creatures.
I'm Gordon, leader of our group.
I'm the village mayor, Hiraku.
He's huge.
Well over two meters tall.
Oh, thanks.
We were expelled from our village
and left wandering until we found help.
They had children with them
and were in dire straits.
I thought that called for urgency.
Best not waste time on small talk.
Let's get some food ready.
Very well.
What's our headcount?
Seventy-two.
Wow...
Please enjoy yourselves.
Thank you!
Rice porridge seemed
safe enough to start with,
but I wonder if there's
anything they can't eat.
My apologies, I am unfamiliar
with the ways of minotaurs.
Think anyone here knows more?
Lizardman
Narf
Sir, if I may.
What is it?
I spent some time among minotaurs
in my last village.
Allow me to see what they need.
Great. By all means.
Do you hail from the mountains?
I've heard the winds are
pleasant in summertime.
They are.
He's a big help.
We should be all set with
the housing we've set up.
I certainly hope so...
Am I missing something?
These aren't the right size, huh?
They do seem a bit...
cramped.
Quite a bit.
This place is packed.
Our guest quarters are just as full.
We'll need to think of something fast.
If we save the new village
for other newcomers...
I've just received word from my father.
Our new residents are en route now.
Great...
Do forgive the abruptness.
What happened?
Weren't you bringing war refugees
to find a new home?
Things took a sudden turn, you see.
I was forced to use teleportation
magic in quick repetition
to move massive numbers to safety.
You really should consider your age, Father.
Hearing you say that
only makes me feel worse...
Go on and rest, then.
Much obliged.
I suppose that means...
our newest residents are
these half-horse centaurs?
Mind your eyes.
Will you not introduce yourself?
I'm Hiraku, mayor of this village.
I am Gruwald of the centaurs.
Kin to Viscount Beeg's chief retainer.
I guess I should assume Viscount Beeg is
some noble from the Demonic Kingdom?
Why do you remain silent?
You have been informed of my standing.
I expect you to take appropriate measures.
You expect us to wait further yet?!
Do forgive us.
You must tire from your journey.
Rest assured you stand now on land
Clerk
Lattiaci
with ties to Count Chrome.
Be at ease.
Very well.
I feel bad, but I don't understand
the rules of the nobility,
so I leave all that to people who do.
Flashback
Viscount Beeg?
He's from out west, yes?
I've never made acquaintance.
Allow me, then.
We were sent word of your move,
but you arrive at the most pressing of times.
Make arrangements nonetheless.
We are beyond worn!
What brings you to us, Miss Gruwald?
If I am not mistaken,
you come seeking our aid.
These lands are not yours
to take command of.
I ask that you reconsider your assumptions.
You speak offense, village girl!
Forgive me, I'd yet to introduce myself.
I am Lattiaci Drowa,
daughter of Count Drowa.
Daughter of the Count?
Might I ask from whence you hail?
Perhaps we ought to
discuss things elsewhere.
IMPORTANT
House of Count Drowa
Viscount Beeg's
Retainer's
Kin
WEAK
Discussions Underway
Forgive my insolence!
It's no big deal.
I ask you to pardon my actions as well.
I beg your forgiveness!
That's enough, really!
Might I ask to be assigned to assist them?
They do have ties to my family, after all.
I'd appreciate it.
But is everything all right back home?
They're in the middle of a war
big enough to create refugees, right?
Your concern is much appreciated.
I've been told there's nothing
to worry over right now.
She's sure taking a while.
Do you get the feeling
she won't be returning?
I thought she was here to help us...
A complete mismatch yet again.
It would certainly be a tight fit.
Can you not grow smaller with magic?
Hrmph! This is the best I can do.
Not everyone is like you, Lu.
Our largest buildings are full already.
I'll squeeze in.
How many of you are there?
Forty adults and sixty-four children
for a total of one hundred and four.
Yikes...
What about the dungeon to the south?
The lamia might let them
stay a while if asked.
What did we build this village for again?
Don't rub salt in the wound.
We've got minotaurs and centaurs.
What other kind of taurs
should we expect now?
While I joked to myself, another group of
young women arrived at our gates.
The lamia found them
moving through the woods.
They were trotting right through the forest,
so I thought I'd bring them here.
They came on foot?
Through all the monsters and
other danger out there?
What's with that stump?
Is it to sit on to rest?
Uh, hi, I'm the mayor, Hiraku.
They're not very talkative.
Maybe they're nervous?
Forgive us.
We aren't used to speaking.
You can call me Igu.
Thank you for having us.
The stump can talk?!
Maybe that shouldn't be surprising.
Turns out these girls were nyunyu daphne.
Wood spirits, of a sort.
They had the ability to
turn themselves into plants
and took tree form whenever
they encountered monsters.
When damaged in tree form,
they lose the ability to take
humanoid form again for some time.
But why a stump?
For easier transport.
Portable form, huh?
Our lands met with floods after humans
cut down most of the trees.
We crossed the Forest of Death
after a merchant named Michael
told us of your village.
I see.
Michael probably couldn't tell us much
since you traveled on your own.
You must be hungry after all that walking.
Should we host a feast?
Feast or not, I'd like to
prepare you a meal.
Is there anything you'd like?
We require no sort.
Really, anything.
Fruit.
We can easily get whatever fruit you'd like.
Sir Michael showed us the fruit grown here.
If you can grow such
incredible fruit on these lands...
Soil.
You must have magnificent soil.
You feed on soil?
I showed them to an empty field
as requested but wasn't expecting...
whatever this is.
It's just as fragrant as I'd imagined.
We require no food.
Only clean water, bright sun, and...
Stopped mid-sentence.
...magnificent soil.
Maybe time moves differently
for these wood spirits.
Oh!
We've cleared all food-related matters,
but what about housing?
Finally, new residents for all those houses!
We have houses built and ready.
We require sunny outdoor spaces.
We could add bigger windows for more light.
We prefer the outdoors.
Not all the time, right?
Like when it rains and such?
Out. Doors.
For now, the young minotaurs
have been given the houses,
while the centaurs shared the stables.
The nyunyu daphne,
well, they're still in the field.
Night.
I wonder if I'll ever get used to the sight.
The other village is going to be
empty for a while.
We need to work on getting places
for all these folks for now.
Things will be quite crowded until we do.
We'll need food, clothing,
and other necessities.
Let's start with what we can manage.
Very well.
Yay, more work...
We'll need to design new homes.
Of course! Let's build nice big ones!
For seventy-two minotaurs and
one hundred and four centaurs!
What a ludicrous amount!
We'll make it work.
Now then, Lady Gruwald.
The Discussion They Had
I beg you forgive me for my discourtesy.
No need for apology.
I'm sure you were only acting
in the best interest of your people.
I care not what becomes of me.
But I want our children to be safe,
if you'll have them.
That is up to the mayor, not me.
The man named Hiraku?
The mayor stands above all of us here.
Conversely, I fall near the bottom.
Like a mere grain of sand.
But... You're the daughter of the count!
Why do you imagine Count Chrome,
of the demon lord's four generals,
ferried others here as if he were
a mere workhorse?
I hope you understand how you should behave
around one who merits such action.
Forgive my insolence!
It's no big deal.
Really, though! Stand up, it's fine!
An excellent apology.
Next time
The Newcomers
Episode 2